[Music]
let's not spin in
welcome back ice cream makers today we
are making salt and straws cinnamon
snickerdoodle
now apparently someone said i said
snickerdoodle last time too much
emphasis on the ooh
so for all those people
how about snicker poodle
no we're just gonna make cinnamon
snickerdoodle
it's in salt and straws recipe book it's
online basically everywhere so let's
just get stuck in and make it shall we
so to make the snickerdoodles according
to the recipe book combine the butter
and one cup of sugar in a stand mixer
fitted with a paddle attachment now we
don't have one of those so we're using
our hand whisk thing that you know may
or may not work oh no it's sugar
everywhere again like normal actually if
you watched our last cookie
making video i did the same thing there
i'm not a baker
anyway keep whisking it until that
mixture comes up light and airy lighter
in shade and then add your egg whisk
that in make sure it's well combined
then add the flour the cream of tartar
baking soda and salt now we actually
used
baking powder in the uk baking powder is
baking soda with the acidic element to
it in the u.s baking soda doesn't have
that acid that's why you need to add the
cream of tartar
it's all very complicated
if you're in the u.s follow the recipe
in the description if you're in the uk
use baking powder
and no cream of tartar i'll mention this
properly in the description below
once all your dry ingredients are
incorporated
get it together and then put it in the
fridge now interestingly enough we had
to add another 30 grams worth of flour
to this recipe now whether that's just
the translation between cups and grams
didn't work or who knows but anyway
with the mix in the fridge for a couple
of hours we've taken it out broken up
into small pieces rolled them into nice
little balls and then dropped them in
the cinnamon sugar mix
cover them completely and then get them
in the oven 375 which i think is 180 or
200 i'll put that in the description
below
and cook them for 20 minutes sounds like
a long time but it's the right amount of
time 20 minutes turn them around halfway
through cooking then take them out let
them cool completely put them aside
until later
[Music]
so in salton straw's recipe book they
say to combine the xanthan gum sugar and
your skim milk powder in a bowl so
that's what we're gonna do here as you
can see
once that's all combined
put your corn syrup we've actually used
glucose syrup here because we can't get
corn syrup in the uk put that in the pan
add the milk and then gently warm it up
add your dry ingredients and stir until
all the sugar and skim milk powder is
dissolved nicely then take that off the
heat
put it in a container and add your cream
give that a nice little stir and then
put it in the fridge you need to get
that nice and cold so a good two to
three hours
[Music]
now according to salt and straw's recipe
they recommend taking your ice cream
base out the fridge and then add in your
cinnamon and your chili powder yo chili
pea
now for me this didn't combine well at
all it just clumped up and made a right
old mess back in the fridge they say put
it back in the fridge for 10-15 minutes
and let the spices
dissolve now they don't dissolve they
kind of just clump together so i'd
probably do this a bit different but
we'll talk about that later
once it's all combined
with your ice cream maker chilled down
for 10 to 15 minutes beforehand get it
in your machine churning this recipe is
actually a little bit low in sugar for
me and it didn't take long at all it
took eight minutes to churn in the 50 30
here
your ice cream is churning take your
cookies and cut them up into
half or one centimeter squares you can
get some little crumbly bits in there
too
and keep that aside we're going to add
those to the ice cream while they're
churning once your ice cream is churning
right at the end the last couple of
minutes add in your crumbled or cut up
snickerdoodle cookies make sure it's
well combined if your machine isn't
strong enough like ours then just fold
them into the tub by hand
and look at this tub it's i'm sure this
is modelled around me but we'll talk
about that in a minute as well
[Music]
so the ice cream's been in the freezer
overnight it's sunday morning
and for those eagle eyes i am not
wearing my cookie monster lounge pants
i'm wearing batman ones instead like
i'm batman so let's get some of this ice
cream out freezer dish it up and see
what a bloody snickerdoodle is
[Music]
now if you watch a little clip of me
scooping this actually is pretty hard
this froze really quite hard in the
freezer
why sugars
the recipe
salt and straw use a standard base in
their recipe book and then they add
stuff to that depending on what it is
for me they should have added a little
bit more sugar
with the cookies but they didn't so
that's why it's a little bit harder than
personally i'd like but if you take it
out freezer for five minutes it will be
fine
normally their ice cream recipes are
perfect
so
cinnamon snickerdoodle
look at the tub
this
design is because for this recipe they
use red ape cinnamon which
if you look online you see that they
work tirelessly to help with the
orangutans i can't say orangutans
and we can't get that over here so i've
just used cinnamon from tesco
but
we think this is a great cause and we
wanted to highlight this in this video
just so if you can buy it do buy it
there we go
we also don't even know what a bloody
snickerdoodle is because we don't we
don't get them over here in england we
don't even know it's a thing i had to
look it up and it turns out it's a very
specific type of cookie which obviously
we've made so what does a cinnamon
snickerdoodle taste like
[Music]
quite nice
it's not a deep flavor feel cookie it's
quite a plain cookie but the top has got
the cinnamon and the added sugar on it's
a nice crunch to it
overall it would make a really nice
sandwich for ice cream sandwich
which we may have a couple aside that we
might do that with
tub's gone
stay set to put back in the freezer
otherwise we're gonna waste the whole
thing whilst i do voiceover recording
and everything else so here we go
interestingly enough as you can see the
ice cream hasn't really melted
now
that is partly because it's frozen solid
but
it's also something to do with the
xanthan gum that they use as a
stabilizer but again we'll get on to
that if you're interested in stabilizers
we're going to talk about those in our
chocolate ice cream series later down
the line so make sure you subscribe so
you don't miss any of that fantastic
sciency ice cream action anyway
i think we just dive straight in and see
what this stuff tastes like
[Music]
it's cinnamon it's it's basically a
cinnamon ice cream with
a very slight touch of cinnamon cookie
adding
it's very pleasant it's very nice if you
like cinnamon of course i do
i can't taste the chili powder at all
it's
we had to ask salt and straw how much to
put in because they actually don't
mention it in in the recipe book and
they came back saying it's just a pinch
that pinch has literally done nothing so
if you like chili powder or you want a
bit heat then
go to town put put loads in personally i
don't like spicy food i'm a corma man
through and through yeah
so
up to you how much heat you put into
this but cinnamon great it's actually
texture-wise it's
like you'd expect from saltwater straw
it's a perfect texture it's really
really nice
although it doesn't look like it's
melted it's actually softened up quite
well
it's probably sat here for
six or seven minutes and it's ready to
go
so if you love snickerdoodles and you
even know what that is and it's not a
poodle then make sure you make this
really nice ice cream
it's a really deep luxury cinnamon base
so really nice and tasty i'm gonna sit
here and poodle my way snicker poodle
whatever my way through this ice cream
thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like and subscribe and we'll
see you next week
so if you want to watch another salt and
straw video click this one up here to go
to their salted malted chocolate chip
cookie dough man that's a big title
click this one to watch whatever youtube
recommend and don't forget to do this
one for the subscribe